Now that we understand stream ciphers,\nwe're gonna move on and talk about a more
现在我们已经了解了流密码，让我们继续谈论一个
powerful primitive called a block cipher.\nSo a block cipher is made up of two
更强大的原型：分组密码。一个分组密码由两个
algorithms, E and D. These are encryption\nand decryption algorithms. And both of
算法组成，E和D，分别表示加密算法和解密算法，而且这两种
these algorithms take, as input, a key K.\nNow, the point of a block cipher is that
算法都采取一个密钥K作为输入。现在，一个分组密码的重要的一点是，
it takes an n bit plain text as input, and\nit outputs exactly the same number of bits
它采取一个N比特的明文作为输入，并且它的输出是完全相同的比特数
as outputs. So it maps N bits on inputs to\nexactly N bits of outputs. Now there are
因此它将n比特的输入正好映射成n比特的输出。
two canonical examples of block ciphers.\nThe first one is called triple-DES. In
现在有两种典型的分组密码的例子，第一种就是所谓的三重DES加密
triple-DES the block size, namely the\nnumber of input bits, is 64. So triple-DES
三重DES的分组大小――即输入比特数是64.因此三重EDS
will map 64-bit blocks to 64-bit blocks\nand it does it using a key that's 168 bits long.
将64比特分组映射成64比特分组。并且它使用一个168比特长的密钥
We're gonna talk about how Triple DES is built in the next segment.
我们将在后面再来讨论三重DES是如何构建的。
Another block cipher, which is more\nrecent, is called AES. Now, AES has
另一种更近期的分组密码，被命名为高级加密标准（AES）.AES有
slightly different parameters. So, here\nthe block size is 128 bits.
稍微不同的参数，它的分组大小是128比特
So, AES will map a 128 bits of input to 128 bits of output.
所以AES将128比特输入映射为128比特的输出
And it actually has three possible sizes of keys, and I wrote down these sizes over here.
它实际上有三种可能大小的密钥，我将它们的大小写在这里
Basically the longer the key, the slower the cipher is,
基本上密钥越长，加密越慢
but presumably the\nmore secure it is to break and we're gonna
但据估安全性更高更难破解 并且一会我们将
talk about what it means for block ciphers\nto be secure in just a minute. Now block
讨论保持分组密码的安全性意味着什么。
ciphers are typically built by iteration. They\ntake in as input a key K, for example
现在分组密码通常通过迭代来构建。它们采用密钥K作为输入
in the case of AES the key could be 128\nbits long, and the first thing that
例如在AES的情况下，，密钥可以是128比特长
happens to the key is that it gets expanded\ninto a sequence of keys K1 to Kn called
而且第一步是密钥扩大成从K1到Kn的序列
round keys. Now, the way the cipher\nuses these round keys is by iteratively
称为回合密钥。现在，密码使用这些回合密钥加密的方式
encrypting the message again and again and\nagain using what's called a round
是通过一次又一次迭代加密消息并重复使用，这就是轮函数。
function. So here we have this function R\nthat take two inputs. This function R is
而在这里，这个函数R这需要两个输入。这个函数R
gonna be called a round function. It takes\nas input the round key, and it takes as
就被称为轮函数。它的输入有回合密钥，
input the current state of the message.\nSo here we have our input message. Say,
另一个输入是消息的当前状态。所以在这里，我们有我们输入的明文消息。
for AES, the message would be 128 bits\nexactly, because each block in AES is
再说，对于AES来说，该消息将正好是128比特位，因为每个AES分组正好是128比特。
exactly 128 bits. And then the first thing\nthat happens is we apply the first round
然后首先我们应用的第一个轮函数
function using the key K1 to the\nmessage. And we get some new message out,
使用密钥K1来对消息加密。然后我们得到一个新消息
as a result. Then we take this message m1, we apply the next round function to
作为结果。我们记之为m1，在下一轮轮函数中使用
it using a different key, using the key k2.\nThen we get the next round message out.
不同的密钥K2进行加密。然后我们得到下一轮消息。
And so on and so forth until all the\nrounds have been applied and then the
然后继续这样加密到第四次直至所有轮函数都被用于加密，
final output is actually the result of the\ncipher. And again this would be also
然后得到最终输出就是我们的加密结果。再次的
in the case of AES, this was 128 bits. And\nthe resulting cipher text would also be
在AES的情况下这输出结果将是128比特。并且得到的密文也将是
128 bits. Now, different ciphers have\ndifferent number of rounds, and they have
128比特。现在，不同的加密算法具有不同的轮数和
different round functions. So, for\nexample, for triple DES the number
不同的轮函数。例如，三重DES的轮数
of rounds is 48. And we're gonna see\nexactly how the round function for triple
是48.接下来我们将看到轮函数究竟如何为三重DES工作
DES works. For AES, for\nexample, the number of rounds
对于AES，它的轮数只可能是10
is only ten, and again, we're gonna look\nat how the round functions for AES
并且马上我们也将再次来看看
work as well in just a minute.
轮函数是如何为AES工作的。
Before we do that, I just wanted to mention performance numbers.
在这之前，我想提及一些性能数据
So you can see here, these are the performance numbers
因此你可以看到这些性能数据
for the two typical block ciphers, triple DES and AES.
都是两种典型分组密码三重DES和AES的性能数据。
And these are the corresponding numbers for the stream ciphers
并且这些也是流密码的相应性能数据
that we looked at in the previous module.
我们在前面模块所看到过
And if you see that the block ciphers are
你会发现该分组密码
considerably slower than stream ciphers. But we'll see that we can
比流密码慢得多。但我们会看到，
do many things with block ciphers that we\ncouldn't do very efficiently with,
我们可以用分组密码做很多事情，但如果用RC4却不能有效完成
constructions like RC4. Now my goal for\nthis week is to show you how block ciphers work,
现在我本周的目标是向你展示分组密码是如何工作的
but more importantly I want to show\nyou how to use block ciphers correctly,
但更重要的是我想说明如何正确使用分组密码，
for either encryption or integrity or\nwhatever application you have in mind.
无论是对于加密或完整性或不管什么你能想到的任何应用。
So to show you how to use block ciphers correctly, it actually\nmakes a lot of sense
因此，为了向你们展示如何正确使用分组密码，它实际上使得
to abstract the concept a little bit so we have a clean,\nabstract concept of a block cipher
适当的抽象一点概念更有道理，所以我们对分组密码有一个清晰的，抽象的概念
to work with. And then we can argue and reason\nabout what constructions are correct and
然后，我们可以争辩和推理什么结构是正确的
what constructions are incorrect. And so\nan abstraction, it's a very elegant abstraction of a
什么结构是不正确的。所以分组密码的一个抽象的优雅的概念就是
block cipher is what's called a pseudorandom function, a pseudorandom
所谓的伪随机函数，一个伪随机置换。
permutation. So let me explain what these\nthings are. So a pseudorandom function
让我来解释一下这些概念是什么。一个伪随机函数
basically is defined over a key space, an\ninput space, and an output space.
被定义在密钥空间，一个输入空间，和一个输出空间。
And all it is, is basically a function that takes\na key and an input as inputs and outputs
并且这全部基本上是一个函数,它采用一个密钥与输入作为输入,并输出
some element in the output space. Okay, so\nit takes an element in K, an element in X,
一些在输出空间中的元素。而它需要给出一个密钥K，一个元素X
and outputs an element in Y. And the only\nrequirement essentially, is that there's
并输出Y.而唯一本质上的要求是要一个
an efficient way to evaluate the function.\nFor functions we're not requiring that
有效方式来计算函数。对于函数我们不要求它们是
they be invertible, we just need them to\nbe evaluatable, given the key and the input x.
可逆的，我们只要求在给出的密钥和输入值X的时候它们是可求的。
Now, a related concept that more accurately captures what a block cipher is
现在，一个相关的概念能够更准确地抓住什么是分组密码
it's called a pseudo-random\npermutation. So a pseudo-random
它被称为伪随机置换。这样的一个伪随机置换概念
permutation is, again, defined over a key\nspace, and then just a set X. And what it
再次被定义在密钥空间和一个集和X中。
does is it takes an element in the key\nspace, an element of X, and outputs,
而它的作用是它需要密钥空间的一个元素，X中的一个元素和输出，
basically, one element in X. Now, as\nusual, the function E should be easy to
基本上，一个在X的元素。现在，和通一样，该函数E应该很容易
evaluate. So there should be an algorithm\nto evaluate the function E. But more
计算。所以应该有一个算法来计算函数E.但更重要的是
importantly, once we fix the key K, it's\nimportant that this function E be one-to-one.
一旦我们确定了密钥K，重要的一点是这个函数E应该是一一对应的。
In other words, if you think of the\nspace X as the set here, and here's the
换句话说，如果你认为空间X的集合在这里，并在这里是
same set X again, then basically the\nfunction E, what it does, is, it's a one-to-one
同样的集合X，然后函数E要做的就是一个一一对应
function, so every element in X\ngets mapped to exactly one element in X.
函数，X中的每个元素恰好被映射到X中的一个元素上。
And then because it's one to one, of\ncourse it's also invertible. So given some
然后，因为它是一一对应的，当然它也是可逆的。因此，给定
output there's only one input that maps to\nthat output. And the requirement is that
一个输出只有一个输入与之映射。要求是
there is an efficient inversion algorithm,\ncall it D, that given a particular output,
这是一种有效的反演算法，称之为D，给定一个特定的输出
will output the original preimage that\nmapped to that output. So really, a
将输出原像来映射到该输出。说实话
pseudorandom permutation captures very\naccurately and syntactically what a block
一个伪随机置换精确的反映了分组密码的特点，在语法上
cipher is, and often I'll use the terms\ninterchangeably, either a block cipher or
我经常会使用术语互换来表述什么是分组密码，什么是伪随机置换
a pseudorandom permutation. I'll use\nwhichever term depending on the context
我将根据所在上下文和我们讨论的事情的地点使用任何术语。
where we're discussing things. Okay,\nso we have two examples, as we said, of
所以我们有两个例子，正如我们所说
pseudorandom permutations, triple DES and\nAES, say for AES-128. The key space would
伪随机置换，三重DES和AES，这里说的AES-128。密钥空间将是
be 128 bits and the output space would be\n128 bits. For Triple DES, as we said, the
128比特并且输出将是128比特。对于三重DES，正如我们所说，
block size is only 64 bits. And the key\nsize is 168 bits, okay. So we'll use
分组大小只有64比特。而密钥大小是168比特。好的，因此我们将使用
these running examples actually throughout, so whenever I say a PRP, concretely
这些贯穿整个的运行实例。实际上，每当我说PRP，具体地
you should be thinking AES or\ntriple DES. Now one thing that I
你应该想到AES或三重DES。现在有一件事
wanted to point out is that in fact any\npseudo-random permutation, namely any block
我想指出的是，实际上，任何伪随机置换，即任何分组密码
cipher, you can also think of it as a PRF.\nIn fact a PRP is a PRF that has more structure.
你也可以把它当做一个PRF。其实一个PRP是一个有更多的结构的PRF。
In particular, a PRP is a PRF where\nthe input space and the output space are
特别地，当输入空间和输出空间相同的时候，PRP就等价于PRF了。
the same, so X is equal to Y, and in\nfact is efficiently invertible once you
所以X等于Y，一旦你有私密密钥那它是可逆的。
have the secret key k. Okay. So\nin some sense a PRP is a special case of a
好，所以在某种意义上的PRP是PRF的一个特例。
PRF, although that's not entirely accurate, and we'll see why in just a second.
虽然这不完全准确，我们马上将看到为什么。
So, so far, we just described the,\nkind of, the syntactic definition of what
所以，到目前为止，我们刚才所描述的那些，关于句法定义什么是
is a pseudo random permutation and a\npseudo random function? So now, let's talk
伪随机置换和什么是伪随机函数？所以，现在让我们来谈谈
about what it means for a PRF or a PRP to\nbe secure. And this concept will
这对PRF或PRP的安全性意味着什么。而这一概念
essentially capture what it means for a\nblock cipher to be secure, okay? So this
根本上将阐述了分组密码的安全性意味着什么。所以这就是
is why I wanted to show you these\ndefinitions, before we look at actual
为什么我想向大家展示这些定义，在我们实际看到
block cipher constructions, so at least\nit's clear in your mind what it is we're
分组密码结构之前，至少在脑袋里对我们尝试去构造的东西
trying to construct. Okay, so here we have\na PRF. And I'm gonna need a little bit of
有一个清晰的印象。好的，在这里我们有一个PRF.并且我将需要一点
notation, not too much though, so I'm gonna\nneed to define the set "Funs of X, Y".
标记，虽然不是很多。所以我将需要定义函数X,Y的集合
This is basically the set of all functions from\nthe set X to the set Y, denoted here as a
这是所有函数的基本集合从集合X到集合Y,表示这里作为一个
big circle, Funs[X, Y]. Now this set is\ngigantic. Its size is basically, you know,
大圆圈Funs[X,Y]。现在，这个集合是庞大的，它的大小基本上是，
the size of Y to the size of X, so for\nexample for AES, remember both X and Y
|Y| 的|X|次方。例如对于AES,记住X和Y
would be 2 to the 128, so for AES the\nsize of the set is enormous. It'll be
将是2的128次方.所以对于AES集合是非常庞大的。它将是
2 to the 128 times 2 to the 128.\nSo it's kind of a double exponential.
2的 128次方整体的2的128次方次方.所以这是一种双指数
So this is a gigantic number, this is more\nparticles than there are in the universe.
所以这是一个庞大的数字，比宇宙中所有颗粒还要多
But regardless, we can kind of think of this set abstractly. We never have to kind of
但无论如何，我们可以抽象地来想这种集合。我们从不
write it down, we can just keep it in our head and not worry about computing on it.
需要把它写下来，我们只需要保留在我们脑海里不用担心计算就可以了
So this is a particular gigantic set of the set of all functions from X to Y.
所以这是一个特别庞大的集合对于所有从X到Y的函数来说。
Now we're gonna look at a much smaller set of functions, namely I'll call this set
现在我们将要看看一个更小的函数集合，也就是我会叫它
S sub F, and that's gonna denote the\nset of all functions from X to Y that are
集合S下标F,并且这将表示所有从X到Y的函数的集合是
specified by the PRF as soon as we\nfix the particular key k. Okay so,
由PRF指定的，只要我们固定特定密钥K.所以
we fixed the key k, we let the second\nargument float, and that basically defines
我们固定的密钥K，我们让第二论证浮动，而且基本上定义了
a function from X to Y. Then we're going\nto look at the set of all such functions
从X到Y的一个函数。然后我们将要看看所有这些函数的集合
for all possible keys in the key space.\nOkay, so, if you think about it again,
在一个密钥空间对应的所有可能密钥。所以，如果你再想一次
for AES, if we're using 128-bit keys, the size of\nthis, I'll say S-AES, is basically going to be
对于AES来说，如果我们使用128比特的密钥，这个大小，
2 to the 128, so much, much, much\nsmaller than the set of all possible
我称之为S-AES，基本上是要2的128次方，比从X的Y次方所有可能函数集合小的多。
functions from X to Y. And now, we say\nthat a PRF is secure, basically if a
现在，我们说一个PRF是安全的，基本上如果
random function in, from X to Y. So we\nliterally, we pick some arbitrary function
一个随机函数从X映射到Y。所以从字面上看，我们挑选一些任意函数
in this gigantic set of all functions from\nX to Y. And we say that the PRF is secure,
在这个庞大的从X到Y所有函数的集合。并且我们说这个PRF是安全的
if, in fact, a random function from X to Y\nis indistinguishable from a pseudo-random
如果事实上一个从X到Y的随机函数是不可区分的从X到Y的
function from X to Y. Namely, when we pick\na random function from the set SF.
伪随机函数。就是说，我们从集合SF挑选随机函数
Okay. So, more precisely basically again,
好了，更准确地说一遍
the uniform distribution on the set of pseudorandom functions
伪随机函数集合的均匀分布
is indistinguishable from the uniform distribution on the set of all functions.
在均匀分布的所有函数集合中是没有区别的
Let me be just a little bit more precise,
让我更准确一点
just to give you a little bit more intuition about what I mean by that and then we'll
只是让你们更直观明白我的意思是什么，然后我们将
move on to actual constructions. So let me\na bit more precise about what it means for
继续学习实际结构。所以让我更精确解释一个PRF的
a PRF to be secure. And so what we'll do\nis basically the following. So we have our
安全性意味着什么。所以我们会做的如下。我们会有我们的
adversary, who's trying to distinguish\ntruly random function from a pseudo-random
攻击者，他试图区分真正随机函数和伪随机
function. So what we'll do is let them\ninteract with one of the two. So here in
函数。所以我们要做的是让他们与两个中的一个交互。在这里
the top cloud, we're choosing a truly\nrandom function. In the bottom cloud,
在云顶，我们将做的是选择一个真正的随机函数。在云底，
we're just choosing a random key for a\npseudo-random function. And now what this
我们只为一个伪随机函数选择一个随机密钥。现在这个
adversary's gonna do is he's gonna submit\npoints in X. So he's gonna submit a bunch
对手将要做的是将在X提交积分点。所以他将提交一些X
of Xs. In fact, he's gonna do this again\nand again and again. So he's gonna
实际上，他将反复的做这些事。所以他将
submit X1, X2. X3, X4, and then for each\none of, of those queries, we're gonna give him
提交X1,X2,X3,X4，然后对于每一个询问，我们将给他
either the value of the truly random\nfunction at the point X, or the value of
真正随机函数在x点的值,或者点x的伪随机函数的值。
the pseudorandom function at the point X.\nOkay, so the adversary doesn't know which
好的，所以对手不知道他得到的是哪一个。
ones he's getting. By the way, for all\nqueries, he's always getting either the truly
顺便说一下，对于所有的询问，他得到的总是要么是真正随机函数
random function, or the pseudorandom function. In other words, he's either
要么是伪随机函数。换句话说，他要么
interacting with a truly random function\nfor all his queries, or he's interacting
在与一个真正随机函数交互他所有的疑问，要么
with a pseudorandom function for all his\nqueries. And we say that the PRF is
在与一个伪随机函数交互他的疑问。所以我们说PRF是安全的
secure if this poor adversary can't tell the\ndifference. He cannot tell whether he's
如果这个弱的攻击者不能分辨其中差异。他不能分辨他是
interacting with a truly random function\nor interacting with a pseudo random
在与一个真正随机函数交互还是在与伪随机函数交互。
function. Okay, and we're gonna come back\nactually later on and define PRFs more
好了，让我们稍后再回来然后更精确地定义RPFs
precisely but for now, I wanted to give\nyou the intuition for what it means for PRFs to be secure
但现在我想给你一个直观感觉关于PRFs是安全的这意味着是什么，
so you'll understand what it is that we're\ntrying to construct when we construct
当我们构建这些伪随机函数的时候，你就会理解
these pseudorandom functions. And I\nshould say that the definition for a
我们到底是在构建什么。并且我想说伪随机置换的定义
pseudorandom permutation is pretty much\nthe same, except instead of choosing a
其实差不多，除了不是选择一个随机函数来。
random function, we're going to choose a\nrandom permutation on the set X. In other
我们将要在集合X中选择一个随机置换
words, a random one-to-one function on the\nset X. The adversary can either query this
换句话说，就是在集合X中选择一个一一对应的随机函数。
random function on the set X, or he can\nquery a pseudorandom permutation, and the
攻击者要么询问这个在集合X总的随机函数要么他询问一个伪随机置换
PRP is secure if the adversary cannot\ntell the difference. Okay, so again the
如果他不能分辨其中奥秘的话，那PRP就是安全的了。
goal is to make these functions and\npermutations look like truly random
好，下面，我们的目标是要使这些函数和置换看起来像真正的随机函数
functions or permutations. Okay. So let's\nlook at a simple question. So suppose we
和置换。好，让我们看看一个简单的问题。假设我们
have a secure PRF. So we know this PRF\nF. Happens to be defined in the set X. And
有一个安全的PRF ，记它为F,而且我们知道这个PRF被定义在集合X
it so happens, you know, it outputs 128\nbits every time. It so happens that this
并且它恰好每次输出128比特。那么发生的就是，
PRF cannot be distinguished from a truly\nrandom function from X to  to the 128.
这个PRF不能从一个X到的128次方的真正的随机函数中被区分出来。
Now we're gonna build a new PRF. Let's\ncall this PRF G. And the PRF G is gonna be
现在我们将构建一个新的PRF。我们称之为PRF G,将它定义如下：
defined as follows. We say, if x is equal\nto zero, always output zero. Otherwise,
我们说，如果x是等于0的，总是输出0。否则
if x is not equal to zero, just output the\nvalue of F. So, my question to you is,
如果x不等于0，就输出F的值。所以，我的问题是
do you think this G is a secure PRF?
你认为G是一个安全的PRF吗？
Well, so, the answer, of course, is that its very easy
好了，当然，答案是非常容易
to distinguish the function G from a random function. All the adversary has to do
能区分函数G和一个随机函数。所有的攻击者需要做的
is just query the function at X=0.\nFor a random function, the probability
仅仅是在x=0的时候咨询函数。对于一个随机函数，
that the result is gonna be zero is one\nover 2 to the 128. Whereas for the
结果为零的可能性将是2的128次方分之一。而对于伪随机函数
pseudo-random function, he's always gonna\nget zero. Because at zero, the function is
他总是得到0.因为在0，函数
always defined to be zero, no matter what\nthe key. And so all he would do is he
总被定义成0，不管密钥是什么。因此所有他能做的就是
would say, hey, I'm interacting with a\npseudo-random function if he gets zero at X=0,
他会说，嘿，我正在与伪随机函数互动！如果他在x=0处得到0.
and he'll say I'm interacting with\na random function if he gets nonzero at X=0.
然后他会说:我正在与一个随机函数互动！如果他在x=0处得到非零。
So it's very easy to distinguish\nthis G from random. So what this example shows
因此这非常容易辨别G和随机函数。这个例子展示了
is that even if you have a secure PRF, it's enough that on just one known input
尽管你有一个安全的PRF,仅仅在已知的输入的时候，
the output is kinda not random, the\noutput is fixed, and already the PRF is broken,
输出是有点儿不随机的就足够了。如果输出是固定的，那这个PRF就已经被破解了，
even though you realize that\neverywhere else the PRF is perfectly
尽管你知道其他地方PRF与随机函数
indistinguishable from random. Okay, so\nlet's just show you the power of PRFs.
是完全不可区分的。好了，让我们来展示PRFs的能力
Let's look at a very easy application. I want to\nshow you that in fact pseudorandom functions
让我们来看看一个非常简单的应用。\n我想向你们展示实际上伪随机函数
directly give us a pseudorandom generator. Okay. So, let's assume we have
直接给了我们一个伪随机数生成器。让我们假设我们有
a pseudo random function. So this one\nhappens to go from N bits to N bits. And then,
一个伪随机函数，而它刚好从n比特对应到n比特。然后
let's define the following generator. Its seed space is going to be the
让我们定义以下生成器:它的种子空间将是
key space for the PRF, and its output\nspace is gonna be, basically, t blocks of
PRF的密钥空间，它的输出空间将基本上是t个n比特的分组。
n bits each. Okay, so you can see the\noutput is a total of n times t bits for
好，所以你们能看到输出是一个n倍t比特的总数
some parameter T that we can choose. And\nit turns out, basically, you can do this
对于我们能选择的一些参数T来说。并且结果基本上是，你可以做
very simple construction, this is\nsometimes called counter mode,
这些简单结构，它们有时候也叫计数器
where essentially, you take the PRF and you\nevaluate it at zero, you evaluate it at one,
在主要的地方，你用PRF并在0处评估它，在1评估它，
you evaluate it at two, at three, at\nfour, up to T, and you concatenate all these values.
在2评估它，在3，在4一直增加到T,然后你拼接这些所有的值
That's the generator, okay?\nSo we basically took the key for the PRF
那就是生成器，对吧。所有我们为PRF设置密钥
and we expanded it into n times t bits.\nOkay. A key property of this generator is
然后扩大到n倍t比特。好了，这个生成器的一个重要特性是
that it's parallelizable. What I mean by that\nis if you have two processors or two cores
它是并行的。我的意思是如果你有双处理器或双内核
that you can compute on, then you can have\none core compute the even entries of the
你可以计算，然后你可以用其中一内核计算输出的偶数项
output, and you can have another core\ncompute the odd entries of the output.
用另外一内核计算输出的奇数项
So basically, if you have two cores, you can\nmake this generator run twice as fast as
所以，基本上如果你有双核，你可以使这个生成器运行速度比只有单核
it would if you only have a single core.\nSo the nice thing about this is, of
快两倍。因此这里面的好处是
course, we know that pseudo-random\ngenerators give us stream ciphers, and so
当然，我们知道伪随机生成器给我们的是流密码，因此
this is an example of a parallelizable stream\ncipher. And I just wanted to point out
这是一个并行流密码的例子。并且我想指出的是
that many of the stream ciphers that we\nlooked at before, for example, RC4,
很多我们之前看过的流密码，例如RC4
those were inherently sequential. So even if you\nhad two processors, you couldn't make the
那些都是串行的。所以即使我们有双处理器，你也不能使
stream cipher work any faster than if you\njust had a single processor. Now the main
流密码比只有单处理器工作快。现在主要的
question is why is this generator secure?\nAnd so here I'm only gonna give you a
问题是为什么这个生成器是安全的呢？在这里我只给你们
little bit of intuition and we're gonna\ncome back and argue this more precisely
一点直观感觉，然后回到原来的内容并在之后再来详细讨论下
later on. But I'll just say that security\nbasically falls directly from the PRF property.
但我只想说基本上这个安全性直接由PRF的属性而来。
And the way we reason about security, is we say, well this PRF by definition
我们推导安全性的方式是通过PRF的定义
is indistinguishable from a truly random function on 128 bits.
与128比特真随机函数是不可以区分的得来的。
So in other words, if I take this generator and\ninstead I define a generator using a truly
换句话说，如果我用这个生成器而这个生成器是使用真随机函数定义的
random function, in other words, I'll\nwrite the output of the generator as
再换句话，我将记下生成器的输出作为
f(0) concatenated f(1), and so on\nand so forth, using a truly random function,
f(0)并联f(1),等等。使用一个真随机函数
then the output of the\ngenerator using the truly random function
那么生成器就会的输出就会是真正的随机函数
would be indistinguishable from\nthe output of the generator using
并且无法被从一个使用伪随机函数的生成器中区分开来
a pseudorandom function. That is the essence of\nthe security property of a PRF. But with
这是一个PRF安全属性的精髓。
a truly random function, you notice that\nthe output is just truly random. Because
但是使用一个真随机函数，你注意到那输出就是真正随机的
for a truly random function, f(0) is\na random value. f(1) is an independent
因为对于真随机函数，f(0)是一个随机数值，f(1)是一个独立
random value. f(2) is an independent\nrandom value, and so on and so forth.
随机数值,f(2)也是一个独立随机数值，以此类推。
So the entire output is a truly random\noutput. And so with a truly random function,
因此整个输出是一个真正随机的输出。并且使用一个真正随机的函数
a generator produces truly random outputs,\nand is therefore a perfectly secure
生成器产生真正随机的输出，因此是一种绝对安全的生成器
generator. And so you see how the PRF\nsecurity property lets us argue security.
所以你们看PRF安全属性是如何让我们争论安全性的。
Basically, we argue that when we replace\nthe PRF with a truly random function, the
基本上，我们认为把使用真随机函数的PRF
construction is necessarily secure, and\nthat says that the construction with a
它的结构必然是安全的，这说明这结构更换为使用
pseudorandom function is also secure.\nOkay? And we're gonna see a couple more
伪随机函数的PRF也是安全的，对吧？在之后我们将看看更多
examples like this later on. So now you\nunderstand what a block cipher is, and you
像这样的例子。所以现在你们明白了分组密码是什么，
have intuition for what security\nproperties it's trying to achieve.
并且你们对安全属性想要达到的性能有了直观认识
And in the next segment, we're gonna look at\nconstructions for block ciphers.
在接下来的一段中，我们将来看分组密码的结构。